Then we have a look at the linked list class which is again a subclass of list that means
it still allows duplicates and shares all the common properties with all collection classes,
that stores objects and is growable, shrinkable and it's sortable and searchable as well
but has its own properties like in a linked list now unlike a list on linked list gives you
the flexibility to add elements at the start in between and at the end and remove at particular
positions as well otherwise it shares the same property as in a list because all both of them
are lists, it's quickly going and in fact I'll just copy paste the school so that we just have
the same data and then there's changes to a linked list where I'll do it in the collections
package, new Java class, I'll just call it this time working with linked list right so we'll have
the main method as always and let's just go on and paste this.
So instead of a error list I'll just have this time the linked list and let's have the
polymorph we get same or you can just go for the normal assignment that's fine as well
this is an in-clist you can go ahead and create an integer only list that's perfectly fine
but for now let's use the same example I added Trisha, Trisha, Trisha this would be
added as well why because it's a list at the end of the day it would allow duplicate values
and then you print out the list you can list or size you add one more right and then
list or size again you remove by index you remove by let's just uncomment one of the
removes print list or size and then you can print it out as well right so the differences
are now when you say let's list or add later on you can even say list or add a new stream
object on the top why I have a method at first which is not found in error list this
is a special method in the linked list class so I can just say list add first and I just
add any here for example similarly I could add list dot add by an index again a special
method in the linked list class I can say at three please add in for example I'll just
say added later so that we know this was added later right and even you have list dot
add last this would be added as the last element right and say added and last now let's
go on and just print this list I'll just comment all of this for now okay just print
this out let's run this still Java 8 for each let's say using Java 8 for each okay
so see so any was added as you're seeing as at the top of your list thanks to the special
material and then added later in between right and then added at last as well because
I used at last so these special methods in the linked class similarly you have methods
which is specific to the linked list when it comes to removing and how does that works
I'll say list dot remove is already there right as with a release but now you have remove
last and remove first as well see I'll remove both of them I'll say move first and then
remove by index or remove by an object is already there which was like in the release
let's go on and run this you should not now see the first and lastly they don't exist
they are deleted but this still exists so that a linked list so as I develop now when would
you choose a linked list over a list again the similarity is they both allow duplicates
to be stored because both are subclasses of the list interface the second property is when
you require make now is to be able to add in between at first at last and then with
the remove as well you want to remove at specific positions right and then a linked list again
as a release is an ordered but unsorted collections it orders elements in insertion order
by index.